<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Snap on Merlijn Sebrechts</title>
    <link>/tags/snap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Snap on Merlijn Sebrechts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/snap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to verify the source of a Snap package</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-17-verify-snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-17-verify-snap/</guid>
      <description>Many Snap packages contain two files which allows users to verify what sources were used to build the package.
 snap/snapcraft.yaml is the &amp;ldquo;source&amp;rdquo; of the package. This file was used by snapcraft to build the package. snap/manifest.yaml is a &amp;ldquo;recording&amp;rdquo; of the build of that package. It is similar to the first file, but it includes a lot more information to pinpoint what exact sources were being used. It records the exact package versions of dependencies, the git commit of all source repositories, checksums of any downloaded binary and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there only one Snap Store?</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-08-02-why-one-snap-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-08-02-why-one-snap-store/</guid>
      <description>Snap and Flatpak are the basis of two universal app stores for Linux: the Snap Store and Flathub. Interestingly, Flatpak has multiple repositories: Flathub is the main one but both Fedora and Elementary OS also host their own store. In contrast; there is only one Snap store. Why is that?
 Note: for an introduction into Flatpak and Snap, please read The future of Linux desktop application delivery is Flatpak and Snap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyleft and LGPL in Snaps and Flatpaks</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-07-17-lgpl-copyleft-snaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-07-17-lgpl-copyleft-snaps/</guid>
      <description>The question often comes up of how Snaps and Flatpaks influence copyleft, GPL and LGPL licenses. It is a common misconception that these new packaging formats significantly influence license compliance.
Disclaimer: I am not a lawyer, this is not legal advice.
Distributing your software in a Snap has no effect on GPL copyleft and LGPL compliance.
 It has no effect on copyleft because containers do not trigger copyleft according to the GNU GPL FAQ [see note].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Linux desktop apps need containers</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-07-06-why-snap-flatpak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-07-06-why-snap-flatpak/</guid>
      <description>The Snap Store and Flathub are two universal app stores for Linux. They are very different from how traditional software distribution works. As is always the case with new software, the question &amp;ldquo;why do we need this?&amp;rdquo; often arises. &amp;ldquo;Including software in distribution repositories has worked for so long, so why do we need to change it?&amp;rdquo;
 Note: for an introduction into Flatpak and Snap, please read The future of Linux desktop application delivery is Flatpak and Snap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fundamental difference between Snap and Flatpak</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-07-03-snap-vs-flatpak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-07-03-snap-vs-flatpak/</guid>
      <description>Snaps and Flatpaks are often compared to each other because they both make it super easy for Linux users to get the latest versions of desktop applications. If a Linux user wants to install the latest version of apps like Slack, Krita or Blender, either tool will work just fine. There is one fundamental difference between Snaps and Flatpaks, however. While both are systems for distributing Linux apps, snap is also a tool to build Linux Distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: S4A on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-02-s4a-setup-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-02-s4a-setup-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>S4A, or Scratch for Arduino, is an app that you can use to program Arduino boards using Scratch. You can program robots and LED&amp;rsquo;s without writing any code: all you need to do is drag and drop instructions in the visual programming environment.
Step 1: Install Arduino IDE and S4A The first step is to install Arduino and S4A from the Snap Store.
sudo snap install arduino s4a After that, you need to give the user account on your computer access to USB devices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>