<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Merlijn Sebrechts</title>
    <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Merlijn Sebrechts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Supervision of master&#39;s and doctoral theses</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/theses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/theses/</guid>
      <description>Supervision Sander Borny, Eenvoudig opzetten van gedistribueerde stream analyse tools en algoritmen met Tengu, 23/06/2016 Thomas Clauwaert, Management of polyglot persistent integrations with virtual administrators, 21/06/2018 Thomas De Letter, Data Hub IDE as a Service, 05/09/2018 Karel Vanden Houte, IDE as a Service, 21/06/2018 Lennart Onghena, Optimaliseren van een Kubernetes relatie-orchestrator, 03/09/2020 Gilles Ballegeer, Daif: a machine learning data framework focused on ease-of-use, 25/06/2021 Jan Mariën, Real-Time Collaboration in Jupyter Notebooks, 25/06/2021 Davy Priem, Managing Ingress in a container environment, 25/06/2021 Liesbeth Bogaert, Dynamic framework for multi data stream analysis of spatiotemporal data, 25/06/2021 Wouter Stemgée, Ontwerp en prototype evaluatie van een raamwerk voor het beheren van gevirtualiseerde ICT-labo omgevingen, 25/01/2021 Gauthier Lambert, Collaborative, serverless management of stateful stream processing pipelines on Kubernetes, 01/07/2022 Wim Onderbeke, Collaborative management of Kubernetes applications, 29/06/2022 Tim Ramlot, Optimising memory usage of Kubernetes operators using WebAssembly, 01/07/2022 Bavo Andriessen, Design and implementation of an intelligent framework for edge anomaly detection in distributed systems, 01/07/2022 Robin De Bock, Deploy, Monitor, Decide, Act: automatic rescaling of Kubernetes clusters using Cluster API, 07/09/2022 Lukas Nys, Kubernetes-based platform for automated &amp;amp; scalable data science lab environments, 07/09/2022 Michiel Schram, Automated bottleneck discovery in microservice applications, 07/09/2022 Bert Verstraete, Plumber: collaborative, serverless management of stream processing pipelines on Kubernetes, 03/02/2022 Wim Verwaerde, Inter-organizational management of Kubernetes applications, 07/09/2022 Maxim De Clercq, Lightweight container alternatives for deploying Kubernetes workloads in the edge, 30/06/2023 Jason Deschacht, Distributed fog service placement with user relationship awareness, 30/06/2023 Kevin Van Landuyt, Predictive scheduling of Kubernetes operators using WebAssembly, 30/06/2023 Gaétan Van Acker, Zwerm-gebaseerde distributie van inhoud met behulp van het Gossip-protocol, 28/06/2023 Emiel Van Severen, Standardizing hardware interfaces in WebAssembly, 07/09/2023 Julien Vermeulen, Beschermen van sensitieve informatie in een volledig beheerde Kubernetes cluster, 07/09/2023 Warre Dujardin, Design and Prototype of a WebAssembly-Native USB Interface, 26/06/24 Matthijs De Cooman, Evaluation of distributed edge/fog storage solutions, 01/02/2024 Arne Dierickx, Comparative study of the performance of WebAssembly runtimes, 26/06/2024 Rein Vanbelleghem, CloudNative lab: web-gebaseerde deployment van Kubernetes clusters in het IDLab datacenter, 26/06/2024 Wouter Hennen, Standardizing USB in the WebAssembly System Interface, 27/06/2024 Friedrich Vandenberghe, Advancing the I2C proposal for WebAssembly System Interface, 27/06/2024 Robbe Haegeman, Improving event-based Kubernetes controller APIs, ongoing Gilles Lefranc, Secure and Efficient Management of Containerized Software on Edge Devices with Limited Connectivity, ongoing Lin Tian, Design and evaluation of WASM-based runtimes in the cloud, ongoing Niel Cami, CloudNativeLab: Cluster API integration on ProxMox / Slices infrastructure, ongoing Alexander Ceule, Inzetten van kunstmatige intelligentiemodellen op ingebedde IoT-apparaten door middel van WebAssembly, ongoing Xander Desoete, Improving kube-rs operators for event-based wasm execution, ongoing Matteo Holvoet, Leveraging AI for Kubernetes System Administration, ongoing Robbe Leroy, Standardizing USB interfaces for WASI, ongoing Thomas Luca, Edge Kubernetes with WebAssembly, ongoing Stef Meert, Design and evaluation of WASM-based runtimes in the cloud, ongoing Bram Van Den Eeckhout, Creating an open source Snap Store, ongoing Wiebe Vandendriessche, Creating a &amp;rsquo;list of ingredients&amp;rsquo; for AI models, ongoing Jarno Vanruymbeke, GPIO and SPI interfaces for WASI embedded, ongoing Robin Verbeelen, Standardizing I2C WASI interfaces, ongoing Joran Verbruggen, Creating an open source Snap Store, ongoing Jonathan Casters, Edge Kubernetes with WebAssembly, ongoing Jury Nico Ekkart, Building a chaos engineering toolkit for cloud-native network functions, 02/09/2020 Jonas Vander Vennet, Using computation graphs for improved network performance in serverless applications, 21/06/2021 Hannes Kunnen, Design of an e-learning platform for active learning of algorithms and data structures, 30/06/2022 Jonas Van den Bulcke, Design of an e-learning platform for active learning of algorithms and data structures, 30/06/2022 Emiel Demeestere, Ontwerp en realisatie van een autonoom dronesysteem voor spoorweginspectie-toepassingen, 30/06/2023 Jordi Thijsman, Design and implementation of an autonomous drone system for railroad inspections, 30/06/2023 Geert-Jan Van Nieuwenhove, Generating DDoS attack data for the purpose of dataset creation, 02/02/2023 Toon De Neve, From individual models to an integrated Data Engine, 03/09/2024 Matisse Callewaert, Real-Time Adaptive Feature Extraction for ML-Based Network Intrusion Detection, 28/06/2024 Steven Jambon, Ontwerp en ontwikkeling van een schaalbare OfficeLab en HomeLab technologie-stack, 26/06/2024 Charly Moerdyk, Vastleggen van realistische DDoS-aanvallen in gecontaineriseerde omgevingen voor dataset-creatie, 28/06/2024 Matthijs Nijssen, Ontwerp en realisatie van een autonoom dronesysteem voor spoorweginspectie-toepassingen, 26/06/2024 Niels Savvides, Heterogeneous Data Generalization in Distributed Intrusion Detection Systems: A Federated Learning Approach, 28/06/2024 Bert Guillemyn, Enabling Industry 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/awards/</guid>
      <description>2024 - Best Paper Award at CLOSER 2024: &amp;ldquo;Feather: Lightweight Container Alternatives for Deploying Workloads in the Edge&amp;rdquo; 2022 - Top Downloaded Article Software: Practice and Experience: &amp;ldquo;Design and evaluation of a scalable Internet of Things backend for smart ports&amp;rdquo; 2022 - Best Demo Paper Award ICWE 2022: &amp;ldquo;Solid Web Monetization&amp;rdquo; at the 22nd International Conference on Web Engineering 2021 - Ubuntu Member (2021): recognition of &amp;ldquo;significant and sustained contribution to the Ubuntu ecosystem&amp;rdquo; 2019 - Best Student Paper Award CLOSER 2019: The paper &amp;ldquo;FUSE: a Microservice approach to Cross-domain Federation using Docker Containers&amp;rdquo; at the 9th International Conference on Cloud Computing and Services Science 2018 - Best Student Paper Award SC2 2018: The paper &amp;ldquo;Unikernels vs Containers: An In-Depth Benchmarking Study in the Context of Microservice Applications&amp;rdquo; at the 8th IEEE International Symposium on Cloud and Services Computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lectures and courses</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/lectures-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/lectures-courses/</guid>
      <description>Conferences Wat is &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; AI nu eigenlijk echt? (event) Science Festival Ghent, 24 November 2024
Wetenschapsfestival - Slimme auto&amp;rsquo;s, zijn die wel veilig? (event) Science Festival Ghent, 24 November 2024
State of the cloud 2024 LSEC Annual General Meeting 2024, 20 November 2024 [invited talk]
WebAssembly for IoT Devices: Interfacing with USB and I2C Hardware (event) WasmCon 2024, 12 November 2024
Cyber-physical WebAssembly WebAssembly Research Center Discussion Series, 7 November 2024 [invited talk]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trainings</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/trainings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/trainings/</guid>
      <description>2023-2024 Agile leadership for post-doctoral researchers Impetus Academy, Fall 2024
Building Collaborative Consortia Masterclass Origanius, Summer 2024
Basisdocententraining (voorjaar 2024)
HORIZON Europe coordinator training (najaar 2023)
2022-2023 Teaching Through English (voorjaar 2023) 2020-2021 Opleidingscompetenties als ruggengraat van de opleiding: het wat en hoe (December 2021) 2018-2019 Assistententraining intervisie (June 2019) [certificate] [end of assistent training UGent] Cross cultural intelligence in academic environments (Februari 2019) Actief en kwalitatief lesgeven aan grote groepen (Februari 2019) [certificate] Assistententraining Lesgeven aan UGent: the basics (Januari 2019) [certificate] The active bystander training (November 2018) De geheimen van een succesvol groepswerk (November 2019) [certificate] Effective Graphical Displays (November - December 2019) 2017-2018 Convincing and Debating (May 2018) Onze studenten krachtiger leren schrijven en presenteren?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llama&#39;s Legal Labyrinth</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2024-08-06-problematic-meta-llama-3-1-license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2024-08-06-problematic-meta-llama-3-1-license/</guid>
      <description>Meta just introduced the Llama 3.1 AI model and accompanied the launch with a blog post explaining &amp;ldquo;Open Source AI is the path forward&amp;rdquo; [a]. But buyer beware: Llama 3.1 itself is a legal labyrinth.
Despite what Meta is implying, Llama 3.1 is not open source. The model is licensed under the Llama 3.1 license and the Llama 3.1 acceptable use policy. These heavily restrict who can use the model and for what purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks &amp; Teaching</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/talks/</guid>
      <description>This is a small selection of recorded talks and guest lectures I gave in the past.
I love sharing my knowledge, both with peers and with the wider public! Contact me if you’re looking for a speaker or guest lecturer on one of these topics.
Open source Keynote: AI is breaking Open Source (recording, slides) Drupalcamp Ghent, May 2024
[Dutch] How open source software is changing the (AI) world (slides, interview recording) Science Festival Ghent, November 2023</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Apache 2.0 LLVM Exception?</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/what-is-the-apache-2-llvm-exception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/what-is-the-apache-2-llvm-exception/</guid>
      <description>Some open source projects use the Apache 2.0 license &amp;ldquo;with LLVM Exception&amp;rdquo; SPDX: &amp;quot;Apache-2.0 WITH LLVM-exception&amp;quot;). So what is the &amp;ldquo;LLVM exception&amp;rdquo; exactly, and why do some projects add it to their license?
Heather Meeker, a notable open source attorney, created this when she was hired by the LLVM foundation to solve two issues with the Apache 2.0 license.
It solves the compiler runtime problem The first issue with the Apache 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A year in the Ubuntu Community Council</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2024-02-17-ubuntu-community-council-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2024-02-17-ubuntu-community-council-year/</guid>
      <description>Let me tell you a secret. When I was elected to the Ubuntu Community Council in the fall of 2022, I had no idea what to expect. I was excited to start working, but I had no idea what I would be working on.
I&amp;rsquo;m clearly not the only person with this issue, given the first question of the Ubuntu Community Council Q&amp;amp;A session at the summit was &amp;ldquo;What does the council actually do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell EcoLoop Pro vs Premier backpack</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2023-12-28-ecoloop-pro-vs-ecoloop-premier-slim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2023-12-28-ecoloop-pro-vs-ecoloop-premier-slim/</guid>
      <description>I bought the Dell EcoLoop Pro, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to.
Dell EcoLoop Pro At the beginning of this year, I bought the Dell EcoLoop Pro Slim and regretted it immediately. The advertising for it is borderline deceptive, in my opinion.
My previous experience with Dell backpacks is that they look stylish and professional, are very handy, and very durable. I&amp;rsquo;ve used my previous Dell backpack for about 6 years, and it&amp;rsquo;s still very useful, although it&amp;rsquo;s starting to look a bit dated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our students can use AI for their master&#39;s thesis - the policy</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2023-05-05-ai-chatgpt-master-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2023-05-05-ai-chatgpt-master-thesis/</guid>
      <description>During my day job, I teach a number of computer science courses in the Information Engineering Technology programme at Ghent University. The release of ChatGPT and GPT-4 has a large impact on our education because it can get grades of above 80% on most exams and can effortlessly write essays on complex subjects. Students are aware of this, and are thus increasingly using Large Language Models (LLMs) in their education for a number of tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Merlijn Sebrechts</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/about/</guid>
      <description>PhD holder and certified cyborg. I enjoy special foods, hiking, and games with a good story. I want to make the world a better place.
I&amp;rsquo;m a senior researcher at imec and teaching fellow at Ghent University in the IDLab research group in Belgium.
Research I lead a number of research tracks focused on software deployment and trust in the cloud and on devices.
Making it easier to deploy and manage complex applications, both in the cloud and on IoT devices Ensuring operators can verify and trust the software running on a device or in the cloud Improving the security of processing sensitive data with confidential algorithms I manage international research projects in collaboration with industry and academia, advise PhD students, coach researchers, and develop research proposals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dell MH3021P speakerphone on Ubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2023-01-24-dell-mh3021p-speakerphone-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2023-01-24-dell-mh3021p-speakerphone-linux/</guid>
      <description>I recently bought the Dell MH3021P speakerphone. I want to use it for hybrid meetings and for recording audio during lectures. Dell doesn&amp;rsquo;t say the device supports Linux, so I was curious to see how much of the device works. Google didn&amp;rsquo;t have an answer so I bought the device to test it for myself.
Thankfully I can say all the important parts work very well out of the box on Ubuntu 22.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can finally disable Snap updates</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2022-11-10-turn-off-snap-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2022-11-10-turn-off-snap-updates/</guid>
      <description>During the Ubuntu Summit, a long-awaited feature was quietly released for preview: You can now completely turn off automatic updates of snaps.
&amp;ldquo;The snap refresh --hold command holds, or postpones, snap updates for individual snaps, or for all snaps on the system, either indefinitely or for a specified period of time.&amp;rdquo;
(currently only available in edge channel of snapd)
This might sound like an obvious feature to many people, but it&amp;rsquo;s a continental shift in philosophy for the Snap developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Kubernetes Operators with WebAssembly</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2022-09-05-wasm-k8s-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2022-09-05-wasm-k8s-controllers/</guid>
      <description>We created a prototype that runs Kubernetes operators in WebAssembly (wasm) and suspends them to disk when they are not used.
Why Developers want to use Kubernetes in the edge, but it uses too much memory for most devices. Running k8s operators in wasm greatly reduces their memory overhead and allows us to start and stop them dynamically. This way, they only run when there is actually something to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Google Drive and Google Calendar as a specific user</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2022-09-10-google-drive-calendar-specific-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2022-09-10-google-drive-calendar-specific-user/</guid>
      <description>Quick tip: did you know you can open Google Drive, Google Calendar and more as a specific user?
Just add ?authuser= and your URL encoded email address behind the address.
For example,
https://drive.google.com/?authuser=merlijn.sebrechts%40gmail.com opens Google Drive as user merlijn.sebrechts@gmail.com. https://calendar.google.com/?authuser=merlijn.sebrechts%40ugent.be opens Google Calendar as user merlijn.sebrechts@ugent.be. This works with almost every google website, including gmail.
Note: you can use an online tool to URL encode your email address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghent University address book in Thunderbird</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2021-08-31-ugent-thunderbird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2021-08-31-ugent-thunderbird/</guid>
      <description>UGent address book support in Mozilla Thunderbird Ghent University has an LDAP address book which contains all students and staff. Adding this address book to Thunderbird is non-trivial, though. Follow these steps to add it.
Install the extensions &amp;ldquo;TbSync&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Provider for Exchange ActiveSync&amp;rdquo;. (Press alt to show the menu and choose Edit &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Add-ons and Themes)
Open TBSync settings, click Account actions &amp;gt; Add New Account &amp;gt; Exchange ActiveSync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to verify the source of a Snap package</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-08-17-verify-snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-08-17-verify-snap/</guid>
      <description>Many Snap packages contain two files which allow users to verify what sources were used to build the package.
snap/snapcraft.yaml is the &amp;ldquo;source&amp;rdquo; of the package. This file was used by snapcraft to build the package. snap/manifest.yaml is a &amp;ldquo;recording&amp;rdquo; of the build of that package. It is similar to the first file, but it includes a lot more information to pinpoint what exact sources were being used. It records the exact package versions of dependencies, the git commit of all source repositories, checksums of any downloaded binary and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I became a cyborg pt2</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-steampunk-cyborg-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-steampunk-cyborg-2/</guid>
      <description>This is part 2 of a series on how I became a cyborg. Warning: this article talks in details about heart surgery and shows post-op images.
Read part 1 first
We can rebuild him 2019-08-06: Waking up from heart surgery.
The first thing I saw were my parents talking to a nurse. My parents wanted to leave but the nurse asked them to stay, saying &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s better to have familiar faces when he wakes up&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there only one Snap Store?</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-08-02-why-one-snap-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-08-02-why-one-snap-store/</guid>
      <description>Snap and Flatpak are the basis of two universal app stores for Linux: the Snap Store and Flathub. Interestingly, Flatpak has multiple repositories: Flathub is the main one but both Fedora and Elementary OS also host their own store. In contrast; there is only one Snap store. Why is that?
Note: for an introduction into Flatpak and Snap, please read The future of Linux desktop application delivery is Flatpak and Snap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyleft and LGPL in Snaps and Flatpaks</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-07-17-lgpl-copyleft-snaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-07-17-lgpl-copyleft-snaps/</guid>
      <description>The question often comes up of how Snaps and Flatpaks influence copyleft, GPL and LGPL licenses. It is a common misconception that these new packaging formats significantly influence license compliance.
Disclaimer: I am not a lawyer, this is not legal advice.
Distributing your software in a Snap has no effect on GPL copyleft and LGPL compliance.
It has no effect on copyleft because containers do not trigger copyleft according to the GNU GPL FAQ [see note].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Linux desktop apps need containers</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-07-06-why-snap-flatpak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-07-06-why-snap-flatpak/</guid>
      <description>The Snap Store and Flathub are two universal app stores for Linux. They are very different from how traditional software distribution works. As is always the case with new software, the question &amp;ldquo;why do we need this?&amp;rdquo; often arises. &amp;ldquo;Including software in distribution repositories has worked for so long, so why do we need to change it?&amp;rdquo;
Note: for an introduction into Flatpak and Snap, please read The future of Linux desktop application delivery is Flatpak and Snap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fundamental difference between Snap and Flatpak</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-07-03-snap-vs-flatpak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-07-03-snap-vs-flatpak/</guid>
      <description>Snaps and Flatpaks are often compared to each other because they both make it super easy for Linux users to get the latest versions of desktop applications. If a Linux user wants to install the latest version of apps like Slack, Krita or Blender, either tool will work just fine. There is one fundamental difference between Snaps and Flatpaks, however. While both are systems for distributing Linux apps, snap is also a tool to build Linux Distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: S4A on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-02-s4a-setup-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-02-s4a-setup-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>S4A, or Scratch for Arduino, is an app that you can use to program Arduino boards using Scratch. You can program robots and LED&amp;rsquo;s without writing any code: all you need to do is drag and drop instructions in the visual programming environment.
Step 1: Install Arduino IDE and S4A The first step is to install Arduino and S4A from the Snap Store.
sudo snap install arduino s4a After that, you need to give the user account on your computer access to USB devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s up with CRI-O, Kata Containers and Podman?</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-01-docker-podman-kata-cri-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-01-docker-podman-kata-cri-o/</guid>
      <description>The container ecosystem is moving rapidly. A lot happened in 2019! It seems the container ecosystem has arrived at the &amp;ldquo;consolidation&amp;rdquo; stage of the hype cycle:
Docker Inc. sold off its enterprise business and had a bunch of restructuring. They shelved Docker Swarm saying &amp;ldquo;The primary orchestrator going forward is Kubernetes.&amp;rdquo; Twitter joined Spotify in moving away from Mesos-based container orchestration to Kubernetes. This was a huge blow to Mesos given Twitter was its original developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I became a cyborg pt1</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2019-steampunk-cyborg-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2019-steampunk-cyborg-1/</guid>
      <description>Close Encounters of the Third Kind &amp;ldquo;We really need to do something about the valve. We&amp;rsquo;ve passed the point where we can wait two more years to see how it progresses.&amp;rdquo;
I was silent for a while, so the cardiologist asked &amp;ldquo;do you understand what I mean?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Like, I need a transplant from a pig heart?&amp;rdquo;, I asked.
&amp;ldquo;Well, given your age an artificial valve is more likely.&amp;rdquo;
It was clear my heart was fucked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who owns my research?</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/copyright-ghent-university-researcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/copyright-ghent-university-researcher/</guid>
      <description>When I submitted my first paper, I realized I had no idea who owned my research! Was I authorized to transfer the rights to a journal or did I need someone else&amp;rsquo;s permission? After some digging, I found the answer and wrote it all up in a neat little document. So here&amp;rsquo;s the dusted off version, in case it&amp;rsquo;s useful to anyone else.
In short Intellectual property (IP) as a PhD student at Ghent University is largely divided into two parts: research results and educational material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Back!</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2019-05-im-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2019-05-im-back/</guid>
      <description>I restored my blog from an old backup I had. I imported it into Hugo, a static blogging platform.
Image by clipart-library</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does “perf interrupt took too long” mean?</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2015-09-perf-interrupt-took-to-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2015-09-perf-interrupt-took-to-long/</guid>
      <description>Wifi problems So, I&amp;rsquo;m having a problem with my laptop. When I&amp;rsquo;m using the “TelenetWiFree” connection, I get disconnected after a certain amount of time, and for some reason I cannot reconnect until I restart my computer. Toggling the hardware Wifi kill-switch, which lets you disable and enable the power to the wifi hardware, does not resolve the problem. After re-enabling the hardware, the wifi doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to come back again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Docker Day 2015</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2015-04-pragmatic-docker-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2015-04-pragmatic-docker-day/</guid>
      <description>I got a ticket to the Pragmatic Docker Day meetup in Ghent in exchange for writing a blogpost about it. Free food, drinks &amp;amp; awesome talks for a whole day, who would want to miss that? Not me!
So here are my unstructured thoughts I gathered from the meetup:
Docker is awesome! What is docker? Docker encapsulates apps in their own little sandbox. Every app runs in its own container. An environment made especially so the app can run well and can&amp;rsquo;t mess to much with other apps running on the same server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows power users are not Linux power users!</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2014-11-why-you-think-linux-sucks-and-why-its-your-own-fault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2014-11-why-you-think-linux-sucks-and-why-its-your-own-fault/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s rid the world of one of the most prominent Linux myths: “Desktop Linux sucks. It&amp;rsquo;s just not there yet”.
When Windows power users try out Linux two things always happen:
They get frustrated because they can&amp;rsquo;t find how to do something in Linux. They brick their system, or make it extremely buggy. I&amp;rsquo;ve been that person, I&amp;rsquo;ve bricked my system (a lot!), and the fact is, it was entirely my own fault.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
