<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Merlijn Sebrechts</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Merlijn Sebrechts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I became a cyborg pt1</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-steampunk-cyborg-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-steampunk-cyborg-1/</guid>
      <description>Close Encounters of the Third Kind &amp;ldquo;We really need to do something about the valve. We&amp;rsquo;ve passed the point where we can wait two more years to see how it progresses.&amp;rdquo;
I was silent for a while, so the cardiologist asked &amp;ldquo;do you understand what I mean?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Like, I need a transplant from a pig heart?&amp;rdquo;, I asked.
&amp;ldquo;Well, given your age an artificial valve is more likely.&amp;rdquo;
It was clear my heart was fucked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run a leaderless organization</title>
      <link>/blog/hackerspace-blueprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hackerspace-blueprint/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who owns my research?</title>
      <link>/blog/copyright-ghent-university-researcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/copyright-ghent-university-researcher/</guid>
      <description>When I submitted my first paper, I realized I had no idea who owned my research! Was I authorized to transfer the rights to a journal or did I need someone else&amp;rsquo;s permission? After some digging, I found the answer and wrote it all up in a neat little document. So here&amp;rsquo;s the dusted off version, in case it&amp;rsquo;s useful to anyone else.
In short Intellectual property (IP) as a PhD student at Ghent University is largely divided into two parts: research results and educational material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Back!</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05-im-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05-im-back/</guid>
      <description>I restored my blog from an old backup I had. I imported it into Hugo, a static blogging platform.
Image by clipart-library</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does “perf interrupt took too long” mean?</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-09-perf-interrupt-took-to-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-09-perf-interrupt-took-to-long/</guid>
      <description>Wifi problems So, I&amp;rsquo;m having a problem with my laptop. When I&amp;rsquo;m using the &amp;#8220;TelenetWiFree&amp;#8221; connection, I get disconnected after a certain amount of time, and for some reason I cannot reconnect until I restart my computer. Toggling the hardware Wifi kill-switch, which lets you disable and enable the power to the wifi hardware, does not resolve the problem. After re-enabling the hardware, the wifi doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to come back again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Docker Day 2015</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-04-pragmatic-docker-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-04-pragmatic-docker-day/</guid>
      <description>I got a ticket to the Pragmatic Docker Day meetup in Ghent in exchange for writing a blogpost about it. Free food, drinks &amp;amp; awesome talks for a whole day, who would want to miss that? Not me!
So here are my unstructured thoughts I gathered from the meetup:
Docker is awesome! What is docker? Docker encapsulates apps in their own little sandbox. Every app runs in its own container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows power users are not Linux power users!</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-11-why-you-think-linux-sucks-and-why-its-your-own-fault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-11-why-you-think-linux-sucks-and-why-its-your-own-fault/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s rid the world of one of the most prominent Linux myths: &amp;#8220;Desktop Linux sucks. It&amp;rsquo;s just not there yet&amp;#8221;.
When Windows power users try out Linux two things always happen:
 They get frustrated because they can&amp;rsquo;t find how to do something in Linux. They brick their system, or make it extremely buggy.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been that person, I&amp;rsquo;ve bricked my system (a lot!), and the fact is, it was entirely my own fault.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>