<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Copyright on Merlijn Sebrechts</title>
    <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/tags/copyright/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Copyright on Merlijn Sebrechts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/tags/copyright/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is the Apache 2.0 LLVM Exception?</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/what-is-the-apache-2-llvm-exception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/what-is-the-apache-2-llvm-exception/</guid>
      <description>Some open source projects use the Apache 2.0 license &amp;ldquo;with LLVM Exception&amp;rdquo; SPDX: &amp;quot;Apache-2.0 WITH LLVM-exception&amp;quot;). So what is the &amp;ldquo;LLVM exception&amp;rdquo; exactly, and why do some projects add it to their license?
Heather Meeker, a notable open source attorney, created this when she was hired by the LLVM foundation to solve two issues with the Apache 2.0 license.
It solves the compiler runtime problem The first issue with the Apache 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyleft and LGPL in Snaps and Flatpaks</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-07-17-lgpl-copyleft-snaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/2020-07-17-lgpl-copyleft-snaps/</guid>
      <description>The question often comes up of how Snaps and Flatpaks influence copyleft, GPL and LGPL licenses. It is a common misconception that these new packaging formats significantly influence license compliance.
Disclaimer: I am not a lawyer, this is not legal advice.
Distributing your software in a Snap has no effect on GPL copyleft and LGPL compliance.
It has no effect on copyleft because containers do not trigger copyleft according to the GNU GPL FAQ [see note].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who owns my research?</title>
      <link>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/copyright-ghent-university-researcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://merlijn.sebrechts.be/blog/copyright-ghent-university-researcher/</guid>
      <description>When I submitted my first paper, I realized I had no idea who owned my research! Was I authorized to transfer the rights to a journal or did I need someone else&amp;rsquo;s permission? After some digging, I found the answer and wrote it all up in a neat little document. So here&amp;rsquo;s the dusted off version, in case it&amp;rsquo;s useful to anyone else.
In short Intellectual property (IP) as a PhD student at Ghent University is largely divided into two parts: research results and educational material.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
